A Guide to the Lyman Creighton Craig papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA134
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Professional correspondence, 1950 1952-1974; 2
  - H-He (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Harvard Cooperative Society, 1 letter
    - Hashimoto, Y., 9 letters
    - Hassall, C.H., 2 letters
    - Hausmann, W.K. At RI 1949-1957, 1952 1955 1963-1967; 19 letters
      Primarily correspondence to others in Dr. Craig's absence. Includes curriculum vitae and bibliography and V. Betina bibliography.
    - Havinga, E., 2 letters
    - Hawk, P.B., 2 letters
    - Hayashi, K., 4 letters
    - Hays, E.E., 1953 1962; 3 letters
    - Hecker, E., 1953-1956 1963; 12 letters
      Professional correspondence between colleges. Some on CCD.
    - Heidelberger, M., 2 letters
    - Heine, H. Support for college chemistry teacher award, 2 letters
    - Heinicke Instruments Co., 1 letter
    - Helfferich, F.G., 2 letters
    - Henderson, J.S., 9 letters
      Lectures: 1973 Dec 11 Winnipeg, Canada Winnipeg biochemical and biophysical society on "Isolation and determination of the structure of active principles" and 1973 Dec 11 University of Winnipeg students in organic and biochemistry on "The search for methods to separate and identify substances from plants and animals" Includes abstract.
    - Hershey, J.W.B. Recommendation for NIH fellowship, 3 letters
    - Hess, G.P. Curriculum vitae and bibliography, 4 letters
  - Hi-Hu (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hickey, F.C., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hickey, R.J., 8 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Includes Hickey ms with Craig comments.
    - Hill, R.J. At RI 1957-1961, 1957-1964; 21 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Includes curriculum vitae with bibliography and nomination for ASBC membership for..
    - Hille, B., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hind, G., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hioe, F.T., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hirsch, R.F. Lecture: 1969 Jan. South Orange, N.J. Seton Hall University "on thin film dialysis", 1969 January; 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hiskey, R.G., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hixon, R.M., 1954 1966; 5 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Includes congratulations on Dr. Hixon receipt of 1954 ACS Midwest award.
    - Hodgkin, D., 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hoffman, P., 11 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Includes curriculum vitae; college and graduate school transcripts.
    - Hofmann, A.F. At RU to 1967, 4 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      [See also under: CCD: correspondence with Hofmann in box no. 15].
    - Holt, C.V., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hoover, A.A., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hope, A.B., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hope, D.B., 1964 1967 1969; 8 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Horiuchi, G. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Horsfall, F.L. Acceptance of Harvey lecture dinner invitation honoring Dr. Gallagher, lecturer, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Howitt, M.K., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Huang, J.H. Curriculum vitae and bibliography, 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hubbell, W.L. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Huber, H.E., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      About improving CCD apparatus.
    - Huber, P.R., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Huebner, C.F., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hummel, L., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Humphrey, J.H., 9 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
      About Craig CCD analysis of the Int'l Reference Preparation for bacitracin for WHO.
      Includes report.
    - Hurley, N., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hurst, E., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Hettinger, Thomas P. At RU 1966-1971, 1966-1972; 46 letters (Box 6, Folder 2)
    Includes curriculum vitae and recommendations for...
  - Hilschmann, Norbert. At RU 1962-1965, 1961-1970; 64 letters (Box 6, Folder 3)
    Curriculum vitae; bibliography. Also includes recommendation for and 1964 Nov 26 Hilschmann report (in German) on investigative work in Craig laboratory; ca. 1964? list of participants of La Jolla, Calif. Salk Institute meeting; typescript with corrections by Craig on"Hilschmann's work on study with Bence Jones proteins", 1964.
  - Hoffmann-La Roche Co., 1956-1970; 2 folders, 91 letters (Box 6)
    Professional correspondence with collaborators; primarily with O. Isler and K. Vogler on work on polymyxin and substance "P". Correspondence with Isler indicates personal friendship.
    Includes various reports from Vogler et al on experimental work; also includes correspondence about Roncari RI staff appointment and evaluations of [See also under: Roncari, G. in box no 12].
    - 1956-1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - 1959-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - I-J (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Indiana University, 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Industrial and Engineering Chemistry, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ing, H.R., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ingram, V., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - International Symposium The Hypophyseal Growth Hormone, Nature and Actions. Detroit, Michigan, 1954 October 27-29; 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Invitation to attend but declines.
      Includes invitation and preliminary announcement.
    - International Wool Textile Research Conference. 1955 Australia, 5 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Includes pamphlet and guide to authors.
    - Interscience Publishers (Box 6, Folder 6)
      [See under: Subject file in box no. 16].
    - Isler, O. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      [See under: Hoffmann-LaRoche in box no. 6].
    - Iyer, G.J., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jacobs, G.J., 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jaffe, Herbert. AT RIMR 1948-1966, 12 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Includes recommendations for..
      [See also under: RU Administration: Spectroscopic committee and laboratory in box no 20].
    - Jahn, T.L., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jain, M., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - James, A.T., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jandorf, B.J., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jardetzky, O., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jeffrey, H.L., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Piatt and Pettersen NIH grant proposals evaluations.
    - Jennings, T.J., 7 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
      About microbalance.
    - Jerussi, R.A., 1 letter (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Johnson, J.H. Curriculum vitae, 4 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jones, J.J., 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jonnard, R., 3 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jorpes, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, 2 letters (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Review of Zeineh et al ms for.
  - Jacobs, Walter A. At RI, 1907-1957; 59 letters (Box 6, Folder 7)
    Correspondence between friendly colleagues. Includes items on Dr. Jacobs collected by Dr. Craig.
    Also includes correspondence about Dr. Jacobs' influence on Dr. Craig as a scientist.
    Includes special interest items:.
    - NY Herald Tribune announcement of award from Belgian government to Dr. Jacobs shared with Michael Heidelberger, collaborators in the discovery of the drug Tryparsamide widely used in the Belgian Congo for treatment of sleeping sickness, 1953 July 7
    - Biographical information for RU Public Information, 1958 January 13 1961 May 25 1965 October 3
    - Jacobs (holograph) congratulatory note on Craig's Lasker award with Craig reply, 1963 October 25
      Includes other Jacob holographs; also some Laura Jacobs (wife).
    - Jacobs/Craig Expression of sympathy on death of David Craig (brother) with Craig reply, 1964 October 1
    - Telegram from Laura Jacobs upon death of Walter A. Jacobs, 1967 July 13
    - NY Times obituary on W.A. Jacobs, 1967 July 13
    - Photocopied carbon copy of letter by Craig/Laura Jacobs upon death of Dr. Jacobs with Mrs. Jacob's reply, 1967 circa July 17
    - Dr. Craig writes Jacobs obituary for American Society for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics. Published in 1968 March in The Pharmacologist., 1967 August 2 1968 March
      Includes copies of obituary [Not listed in Craig bibliography].
    - Photocopies of letter from Mrs. Jacobs/L.C. Craig with "Facts in the Life of Walter Jacobs", 1967 September 9 1967 November 2
      Includes some handwritten notes dated 1967 Nov 2 as additions to this ms by Michael Heidelberger [Originals with Walter A. Jacobs papers].
    - RU Review Obituary biographical sketch of W.A. Jacobs, 1967 November-December
      Includes copies of obituary with working material and Heidelberger's corrections [Not listed in Craig bibliography].
      [See also under: 1967 Nov/Dec. mss not listed in Craig bibliography in box no. 32].
    - W.A. Jacobs bibliography sent by A.V. Astin of NAS to assist Dr. Craig in writing Biographical sketch of W.A. Jacobs; apparently never completed due to ill health, 1973 February 16
      [See Walter A. Jacobs papers for photocopies of some of this material].
  - Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1952-1968; 40 letters (Box 6, Folder 8)
    Reviews of mss submitted for publication and submitting mss for publication.
    (Undated reviews kept in order found).
  - Journal of Organic Chemistry (120) 1953-1967. Member of Board of Editors of (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Includes agendas and minutes of meetings, financial reports and miscellaneous items. Includes reviews of mss submitted for publication and submitting mss for publication.
  - Journal of the American Chemical Society, 1952-1973; 144 letters (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Reviews of mss submitted for publication and submitting mss for publication with referees comments. Undated reviews kept in order found. Includes book reviews [not listed in Craig bibliography].
    [Typescripts and photocopies of these book reviews: See under: Craig mss not listed in Craig bibliography in box nos. 31 and 32].
    1. Rauen, H.M. and Stamm, W. "Gegenstrom-Verteilung" 1953 Springer-Verlag, Berlin. JACS 76 (1954) 4055-4056.
    2. Harris, Marrian and Thurmann eds. "Vitamins and Hormones" Vol. XVI. JACS 81 (1959) 4759-4760.
  - K (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kaarik, K., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Rabat, E.A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kac, M., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Includes B. Hetnarskie curriculum vitae.
    - Kaczka, E.A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kahn, J.R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kamikubo, T., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kammermeyer, K., 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kang, S.H., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kapoor, P.P., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Karush, F., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kassell, B., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Katchalski, E., 1955 1964; 5 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Katsoyannis, P.G., 1965 November 8-10; 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Meeting: 1965 Nov 8-10 Upton, NY Brookhaven Natl Laboratory symposium on structure and function of polypeptide hormones: insulin.
    - Kattwinkel, J., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Katz, S., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kauzmann, W., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kay-Fries Chemicals, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kegeles, G., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kelsey, D.R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy, Joseph P. Jr. Foundation, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kenner, G.W., 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kent, Joan. RU student, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Comments on thesis.
    - Kepes, A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Khorana, H.G., 8 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kies, M.W., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Killion, P.J., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Review of Natl Foundation-March of Dimes grant application for.
    - Kimmel, J.R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kirner, W.R. Recommendations for NSF grant award continuation for F.C. Uhle, 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kitchell, R.L., 1954 1966; 7 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Klein, R.M., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Koffler, H., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kominz, D.R., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kormendy, C.G., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kosak, A.I., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Koshland, D.E. Photocopy of Thomas and Koshland ms with comments about Craig machine, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kouchkovsky, Y. de, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Krantz, A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Krayer, O., 1953 1957 1964-1968; 13 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kriek, H.R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Includes Chen et al published paper.
    - Kreiter, V.P., 11 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kroner, T.D., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kugelmass, I.N., 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kuhn, W., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Kutzky, R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - King, T.P. At RU from 1953-. (Faculty), 1953-1971; 28 letters (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Curriculum vitae with bibliography; college and graduate school transcripts; Includes recommendations for; summaries of King's investigative work and undated (possibly 1960?) copy of King presentation.
  - Konigsberg, William. At RI 1956-1964, 1955-1969; 40 letters (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Curriculum vitae with bibliographies; college and graduate school transcripts. Includes recommendations for; nominations for Harvey Society and ASBC memberships; copy of Konigsberg 1963-1964 research report.
  - L-Lu (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lab-Line Instruments Inc., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Laboratory Glass and Instruments Corp., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lahav, G., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Laiken, Stuart. RU student, 14 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes recommendations for medical school admission.
    - Laitinen, H.A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Laland, S.G., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lande, S., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Langlyke, A.F., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Langridge, R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Larsen, P.O., 18 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes curriculum vitae with bibliography and 6 Larsen et al reprints.
    - Lasker, Mary, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lauer, W., 1955 October 6; 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Meeting: 1955 Oct 6 Minneapolis, Minn. ACS meeting "Title?".
    - Laug, O., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Laurent, P.A., 7 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lauson, H.D. Recommendation for W. Hausmann for Harvey Society membership, 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes Hausmann bibliography.
    - Lawrence University, 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lazarow, A., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lederer, E., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lee, F.C. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lee, M.O., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lee, Y.C., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lembeck, F., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lennox, S.M., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Leonard, N.J., 11 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes review of Kirkegaard and Agee ms for submission to PNAS.
    - Li, C.H., 1953-1974; 32 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes recommendations for; also recommendation for H. Rasmussen; Li and kornberg biographical note for RU lectures; Craig invited to 1967 Sept. Milan, Italy, Intl symp on growth hormone, but declines, includes preliminary program.
    - Li, N.N. (Box 7, Folder 5)
      [See under: Esso Research and Engineering Co in Box no. 4].
    - Lightbown, J.W., 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lin, K-T.D., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Linderstrm-Lang, K. Lecture: 1952 Nov 24 Copenhagen, Denmark, Carlsberg Laboratorium "The use of fractionation techniques in structural studies with polypeptides", 1952 November 24; 8 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lipmann, F.A., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Liquori, A.M., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Little, A., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Little, Dr. and Mrs. H., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Liu, S.Y. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lo, L.W., 3 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lockhart, I.M., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Long, R.B., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lostroh, A.J., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lovrien, R., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Low, B., 2 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Lowry, O.H., 1 letter (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Luck, M.J., 4 letters (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lasker Awards, Albert, 1964-1971; 57 letters (Box 7)
    Dr. Craig on nominating committee; and in 1971 also served on jury to select winners of Lasker awards.
    - Nominations for basic medical research award (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Includes: biographies; bibliographies; description of work; summaries of reasons for nomination for possible award of following:.
      - Oliver Smithies, 1964
      - Robert W. Holley, 1965
      - Marshall W. Nirenberg, 1967
      - Leonard Skeggs, 1968
      - R. Bruce Merrifield, 1969
        Includes copy of citation on Merrifield to Lasker Foundation possibly by Craig.
    - Correspondence, 1971; 2 folders (Box 7)
      Also includes: pamphlets about nominations and awards recipients and confidential booklet of nominations for 1971 Lasker medical research awards; 1971 jury meeting program and membership list; announcement and sketches of scientific work of 1971 winners (E.D. Fries, S. Benzer and C. Yanofsky); also biographical sketches with bibliographies of Benzer and Yanofsky; possible Craig typescript at 1971 awards in basic research presentation to Benzer, Brenner and Yanofsky.
      - 1964-1970 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Lily Research Laboratories, 1953 May 11-12; 29 letters (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Correspondence primarily with O.K. Behrens. Meetings: 1953 May 11-12 Indianapolis, Ind.
  - Lily Res Lab insulin conference, 1955 May 12-13 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    Indications are Dr. Craig presents paper and 1955 May 12-13 insulin conference. May 13 "Structure of insulin". Includes program [See also under: Lab data. Insulin in box no. 41].
  - M-Ma (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mac, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McCleary, CD. Lecture: 1956 February New Haven ACS section, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McClure, R.J. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - MacFadyen, D., 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McFarland, R., 1962 March 21-29; 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Meeting: 1962 Mar 21-29 Washington, D.C 141 ACS meeting "Diffusion through cellophane membranes".
    - McGuntrum, M., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mack Printing Co., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mackay, D.A.M., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McKay, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McLafferty, F.W., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McLaren, A.D., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Maclaren, J.A. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - McNinch, J.H., 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Macorini, E., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Magnusson, S., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mahboob, S. Curriculum vitae, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mahoney, C., 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mair, B.J., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mandel, Professor, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mandl, I., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marcus, A.J., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marchessault, R.H., 8 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mark, H.F., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marlowe, G.J., 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marmur, J., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marsden, N.V.B., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Marshall, L.M., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Masuda, Y., 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mattson, A.M., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mautner, H.C., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mayuranathan, P.S., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Mazel, P., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Me - My (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Means, P., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mehltretter, C.L., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Congratulations on Craig receiving Benedetti-Pichler award.
    - Meier, J.I. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Meinwald, J., 10 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Correspondence between friendly colleagues. Includes biographical sketch of Franz Sondheimer.
    - Meister, A., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Meleney, V., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Menkin, V., 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Merck, Sharp and Dohme, 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Metzsch, F.A. von, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Meyer, P., 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Miller, H.M. Recommendation for A. Paladini, 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Miller, Neal E. RU Professor, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Includes Miller reprint "The brain's critical periods" for UNESCO and Miller comments on need for program on the development of behavior at RU.
    - Milton, M.E., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Minrath, W.R., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mishra, R.K., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mitz, M.A., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Monet, G.P., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Monti, S.A. Curriculum vitae with bibliography, 12 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Moore, Stanford. RU Professor. Evaluation of and recommendation for, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Morawetz, H., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Morehouse, W., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Morison, R.S., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Moritz, C., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Morris, C.J.O.R., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Morris, S.J., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mosbach, E.H., 4 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mosse, J., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Muccino, R.R. Curriculum vitae, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mueller, P., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Mukherjee, R. Curriculum vitae, 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Murachi, T., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Murai, K., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Murray, K.E., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Myers, J., 3 letters (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Manning, James M. At RU, 1967; 34 letters (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Correspondence deals with promotion recommendations from S. Moore, W. Stein, A. Meister, E. Snell, R.F. Hirschmann, E. Smith. Includes biographical material with bibliography.
  - Marfey, Peter S. (111). At RI 1956-1959, 1956-1969; 2 folders (Box 8)
    Reprints. Abstract of paper and program for Woods Hole meeting 1958 Aug 25 and abstract with figures and data on luciferin work. Includes biographical material, recommendations.
    - 1956-1959 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Meinardi, Harry. RU graduate student Professional correspondence between friends, 1963-1969; 40 letters (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Includes curriculum vitae and Meeting: 1965 Oct 25-29 Florence, Italy, Intl symposium on hypotensive polypeptides; Oct 29 Meinardi and Craig "Studies on the purification of substance P" with programs of symposium. Also includes 1963-64 and 1965 progress reports; laboratory notes; typescript of lab procedure; and Craig handwritten notes on Meinardi progress.
  - Merrifield, E. Bruce. RU Professor. Nominates for 1973 Nichols Medal award, 10 letters (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Includes biographical sketch with bibliography and pamphlet of 1969 Albert Lasker medical research award (Merrifield 1969 Lasker basic research award winner) [See also under: Lasker Awards in box no 7].
  - N-No (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Narita, K., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nash, H.A., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nason, A., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - National Drug Co., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - NIAD Allergen Standardization Committee. Dr. Craig member of, 5 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - National Foundation. 1941-1961 list cf National Foundation research fellows, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nature, 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Review of ms for publication in.
    - Neidlemann, M., 1 letter (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nelson, W.L., 2 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Nemethy, George. At RU, 1963-1972; 23 letters (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Curriculum vitae with bibliography and recommendations for.